<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Table>
   <Row>
      <Cell>Author</Cell>
      <Cell>Title</Cell>
      <Cell>Synopsis</Cell>
      <Cell>Continent</Cell>
      <Cell>Country</Cell>
   </Row>
   <Row>
      <Cell>Achebe, Chinua</Cell>
      <Cell>The African Trilogy</Cell>
      <Cell>In these masterly novels, Achebe brilliantly imagines the lives of three generations of an African community as their world is upended by the forces of colonialism from the first arrival of the British to the waning days of empire.The trilogy opens with the groundbreaking "Things Fall Apart", the tale of Okonkwo, a hero in his village, whose clashes with missionaries--coupled with his own tragic pride--lead to his fall from grace. "Arrow of God" takes up the ongoing conflict between continuity and change as Ezeulu, the headstrong chief priest, finds his authority is under threat from rivals and colonial functionaries. But he believes himself to be untouchable and is determined to lead his people, even if it is towards their own destruction. Finally, in "No Longer at Ease", Okonkwo's grandson, educated in England, returns to a civil-service job in Lagos, only to see his morality erode as he clings to his membership in the ruling elite. Drawing on the traditional Igbo tales of Achebe's youth, The African Trilogy is a literary landmark, a mythic and universal tale of modern Africa.</Cell>
      <Cell>Africa</Cell>
      <Cell>Nigeria</Cell>
   </Row>
   <Row>
      <Cell>Ayobami, Adebayo</Cell>
      <Cell>Stay With Me</Cell>
      <Cell>This unforgettable novel set in Nigeria gives voice to both husband and wife as they tell the story of their marriage--and the forces that threaten to tear it apart. Yejide and Akin have been married since they met and fell in love at university. Though many expected Akin to take several wives, he and Yejide have always agreed: polygamy is not for them. But four years into their marriage--after consulting fertility doctors and healers, trying strange teas and unlikely cures--Yejide is still not pregnant. She assumes she still has time--until her family arrives on her doorstep with a young woman they introduce as Akin's second wife. Furious, shocked, and livid with jealousy, Yejide knows the only way to save her marriage is to get pregnant. Which, finally, she does--but at a cost far greater than she could have dared to imagine. An electrifying novel of enormous emotional power, Stay With Me asks how much we can sacrifice for the sake of family.</Cell>
   </Row>
   <Row>
      <Cell>Adichie, Chimamanda Ngozi</Cell>
      <Cell>Americanah</Cell>
      <Cell>A powerful, tender story of race and identity by Chimamanda Ngozi Adichie, the award-winning author of Half of a Yellow Sun. Ifemelu and Obinze are young and in love when they depart military-ruled Nigeria for the West. Beautiful, self-assured Ifemelu heads for America, where despite her academic success, she is forced to grapple with what it means to be black for the first time. Quiet, thoughtful Obinze had hoped to join her, but with post-9/11 America closed to him, he instead plunges into a dangerous, undocumented life in London. Fifteen years later, they reunite in a newly democratic Nigeria, and reignite their passion—for each other and for their homeland. </Cell>
      <Cell>Africa</Cell>
      <Cell>Nigeria</Cell>
   </Row>
   <Row>
      <Cell>Adichie, Chimamanda Ngozi</Cell>
      <Cell>Half of a Yellow Sun</Cell>
      <Cell>"Half of a Yellow Sun" illuminates a seminal moment in modern African history: Biafra's impassioned struggle to establish an independent republic in southeastern Nigeria during the late 1960s. We experience this tumultuous decade alongside five unforgettable characters: Ugwu, a thirteen-year-old houseboy who works for Odenigbo, a university professor full of revolutionary zeal; Olanna, the professor’s beautiful young mistress who has abandoned her life in Lagos for a dusty town and her lover’s charm; and Richard, a shy young Englishman infatuated with Olanna’s willful twin sister Kainene. Half of a Yellow Sun is a tremendously evocative novel of the promise, hope, and disappointment of the Biafran war.</Cell>
      <Cell>Africa</Cell>
      <Cell>Nigeria</Cell>
   </Row>
   <Row>
      <Cell>Arimah, Leslie Nneka</Cell>
      <Cell>What It Means When a Man Falls From the Sky: Stories</Cell>
      <Cell>A dazzlingly accomplished debut collection explores the ties that bind parents and children, husbands and wives, lovers and friends to one another and to the places they call home.  In “Who Will Greet You at Home,” a woman desperate for a child weaves one out of hair, with unsettling results. In “Wild,” a disastrous night out shifts a teenager and her Nigerian cousin onto uneasy common ground. In "The Future Looks Good," three generations of women are haunted by the ghosts of war, while in "Light," a father struggles to protect and empower the daughter he loves. And in the title story, in a world ravaged by flood and riven by class, experts have discovered how to "fix the equation of a person" - with rippling, unforeseen repercussions.  Evocative, playful, subversive, and incredibly human, What It Means When a Man Falls from the Sky heralds the arrival of a prodigious talent with a remarkable career ahead of her.</Cell>
      <Cell>North America</Cell>
      <Cell>United States</Cell>
   </Row>
   <Row>
      <Cell>de Assis, Machado</Cell>
      <Cell>The Collected Stories</Cell>
      <Cell>Predominantly set in the late nineteenth-century aspiring world of Rio de Janeiro―a city in the midst of an intense transformation from colonial backwater to imperial metropolis―the postcolonial realism of Machado’s stories anticipates a dominant theme of twentieth-century literature. Readers witness the bourgeoisie of Rio both at play, and, occasionally, attempting to be serious, as depicted by the chief character of “The Alienist,” who makes naively grandiose claims for his Brazilian hometown at the expense of the cultural capitals of Europe. Signifiers of new wealth and social status abound through the landmarks that populate Machado’s stories, enlivening a world in the throes of transformation: from the elegant gardens of Passeio Público and the vibrant Rua do Ouvidor―the long, narrow street of fashionable shops, theaters and cafés, “the Via Dolorosa of long-suffering husbands”―to the port areas of Saúde and Gamboa, and the former Valongo slave market.</Cell>
      <Cell>South America</Cell>
      <Cell>Brazil</Cell>
   </Row>
   <Row>
      <Cell>Baldwin, James</Cell>
      <Cell>Another Country</Cell>
      <Cell>Set in Greenwich Village, Harlem, and France, among other locales, Another Country is a novel of passions--sexual, racial, political, artistic--that is stunning for its emotional intensity and haunting sensuality, depicting men and women, blacks and whites, stripped of their masks of gender and race by love and hatred at the most elemental and sublime. In a small set of friends, Baldwin imbues the best and worst intentions of liberal America in the early 1970s.</Cell>
      <Cell>North America</Cell>
      <Cell>United States</Cell>
   </Row>
   <Row>
      <Cell>Baldwin, James</Cell>
      <Cell>Giovanni's Room</Cell>
      <Cell>Set in the 1950s Paris of American expatriates, liaisons, and violence, a young man finds himself caught between desire and conventional morality. With a sharp, probing imagination, James Baldwin's now-classic narrative delves into the mystery of loving and creates a moving, highly controversial story of death and passion that reveals the unspoken complexities of the human heart.</Cell>
      <Cell>North America</Cell>
      <Cell>United States</Cell>
   </Row>
   <Row>
      <Cell>Baldwin, James</Cell>
      <Cell>Going To Meet The Man</Cell>
      <Cell>The men and women in these eight short fictions grasp this truth on an elemental level, and their stories, as told by James Baldwin, detail the ingenious and often desperate ways in which they try to keep their head above water. It may be the heroin that a down-and-out jazz pianist uses to face the terror of pouring his life into an inanimate instrument. It may be the brittle piety of a father who can never forgive his son for his illegitimacy. Or it may be the screen of bigotry that a redneck deputy has raised to blunt the awful childhood memory of the day his parents took him to watch a black man being murdered by a gleeful mob.By turns haunting, heartbreaking, and horrifying--and informed throughout by Baldwin's uncanny knowledge of the wounds racism has left in both its victims and its perpetrators--Going to Meet the Man is a major work by one of our most important writers.</Cell>
      <Cell>North America</Cell>
      <Cell>United States</Cell>
   </Row>
   <Row>
      <Cell>Baldwin, James</Cell>
      <Cell>Go Tell It On the Mountain</Cell>
      <Cell> With lyrical precision, psychological directness, resonating symbolic power, and a rage that is at once unrelenting and compassionate, Baldwin chronicles a fourteen-year-old boy’s discovery of the terms of his identity as the stepson of the minister of a storefront Pentecostal church in Harlem one Saturday in March of 1935. Baldwin’s rendering of his protagonist’s spiritual, sexual, and moral struggle of self-invention opened new possibilities in the American language and in the way Americans understand themselves.</Cell>
      <Cell>North America</Cell>
      <Cell>United States</Cell>
   </Row>
   <Row>
      <Cell>Baldwin, James</Cell>
      <Cell>If Beale Street Could Talk</Cell>
      <Cell>In this honest and stunning novel, James Baldwin has given America a moving story of love in the face of injustice. Told through the eyes of Tish, a nineteen-year-old girl, in love with Fonny, a young sculptor who is the father of her child, Baldwin’s story mixes the sweet and the sad. Tish and Fonny have pledged to get married, but Fonny is falsely accused of a terrible crime and imprisoned. Their families set out to clear his name, and as they face an uncertain future, the young lovers experience a kaleidoscope of emotions–affection, despair, and hope. In a love story that evokes the blues, where passion and sadness are inevitably intertwined, Baldwin has created two characters so alive and profoundly realized that they are unforgettably ingrained in the American psyche.</Cell>
      <Cell>North America</Cell>
      <Cell>United States</Cell>
   </Row>
   <Row>
      <Cell>Baldwin, James</Cell>
      <Cell>Just Above My Head</Cell>
      <Cell>he stark grief of a brother mourning a brother opens this novel with a stunning, unforgettable experience.  Here, in a monumental saga of love and rage, Baldwin goes back to Harlem, to the church of his groundbreaking novel Go Tell It on the Mountain, to the homosexual passion of Giovanni's Room, and to the political fire that enflames his nonfiction work.  Here, too, the story of gospel singer Arthur Hall and his family becomes both a journey into another country of the soul and senses--and a living contemporary history of black struggle in this land.</Cell>
      <Cell>North America</Cell>
      <Cell>United States</Cell>
   </Row>
   <Row>
      <Cell>Baldwin, James</Cell>
      <Cell>Tell Me How Long the Train's Been Gone</Cell>
      <Cell>At the height of his theatrical career, the actor Leo Proudhammer is nearly felled by a heart attack. As he hovers between life and death, Baldwin shows the choices that have made him enviably famous and terrifyingly vulnerable.     For between Leo's childhood on the streets of Harlem and his arrival into the intoxicating world of the theater lies a wilderness of desire and loss, shame and rage. An adored older brother vanishes into prison. There are love affairs with a white woman and a younger black man, each of whom will make irresistible claims on Leo's loyalty. And everywhere there is the anguish of being black in a society that at times seems poised on the brink of total racial war. Overpowering in its vitality, extravagant in the intensity of its feeling, Tell Me How Long the Train's Been Gone is a major work of American literature.  </Cell>
      <Cell>North America</Cell>
      <Cell>United States</Cell>
   </Row>
   <Row>
      <Cell>Beatty, Paul</Cell>
      <Cell>The Sellout</Cell>
      <Cell>Born in the "agrarian ghetto" of Dickens―on the southern outskirts of Los Angeles―the narrator of The Sellout resigns himself to the fate of lower-middle-class Californians: "I'd die in the same bedroom I'd grown up in, looking up at the cracks in the stucco ceiling that've been there since '68 quake." Raised by a single father, a controversial sociologist, he spent his childhood as the subject in racially charged psychological studies. He is led to believe that his father's pioneering work will result in a memoir that will solve his family's financial woes. But when his father is killed in a police shoot-out, he realizes there never was a memoir. All that's left is the bill for a drive-thru funeral.Fuelled by this deceit and the general disrepair of his hometown, the narrator sets out to right another wrong: Dickens has literally been removed from the map to save California from further embarrassment. Enlisting the help of the town's most famous resident―the last surviving Little Rascal, Hominy Jenkins―he initiates the most outrageous action conceivable: reinstating slavery and segregating the local high school, which lands him in the Supreme Court.</Cell>
      <Cell>North America</Cell>
      <Cell>United States</Cell>
   </Row>
   <Row>
      <Cell>Beatty, Paul</Cell>
      <Cell>Tuff</Cell>
      <Cell> Weighing in at 320 pounds, Winston “Tuffy” Foshay, is an East Harlem denizen who breaks jaws and shoots dogs and dreams of millions from his idea Cap’n Crunch: The Movie, starring Danny DeVito. His best friend is a disabled Muslim who wants to rob banks, his guiding light is an ex-hippie Asian woman who worked for Malcolm X, and his wife, Yolanda, he married from jail over the phone. Shrewdly comical as this dazzling novel is, it turns acerbically sublime when the frustrated Tuffy agrees to run for City Council. Smartly irreverent and edgily fierce, Tuff is a bona fide original.</Cell>
      <Cell>North America</Cell>
      <Cell>United States</Cell>
   </Row>
   <Row>
      <Cell>Beatty, Paul</Cell>
      <Cell>White Boy Shuffle</Cell>
      <Cell>An awkward, Black surfer bum who is moved by his mother from Santa Monica to urban West Los Angeles. There, he begins to undergo a startling transformation from neighborhood outcast to basketball superstar, and eventually to reluctant messiah of a "divided, downtrodden people."</Cell>
      <Cell>North America</Cell>
      <Cell>United States</Cell>
   </Row>
   <Row>
      <Cell>Bennett, Britt</Cell>
      <Cell>Mothers, The</Cell>
      <Cell>Set within a contemporary Black community in Southern California, Brit Bennett's mesmerizing first novel is an emotionally perceptive story about community, love, and ambition. It begins with a secret."All good secrets have a taste before you tell them, and if we'd taken a moment to swish this one around our mouths, we might have noticed the sourness of an unripe secret, plucked too soon, stolen and passed around before its season."It is the last season of high school life for Nadia Turner, a rebellious, grief-stricken, seventeen-year-old beauty. Mourning her own mother's recent suicide, she takes up with the local pastor's son. Luke Sheppard is twenty-one, a former football star whose injury has reduced him to waiting tables at a diner. They are young; it's not serious. But the pregnancy that results from this teen romance—and the subsequent cover-up—will have an impact that goes far beyond their youth. As Nadia hides her secret from everyone, including Aubrey, her God-fearing best friend, the years move quickly. Soon, Nadia, Luke, and Aubrey are full-fledged adults and still living in debt to the choices they made that one seaside summer, caught in a love triangle they must carefully maneuver, and dogged by the constant, nagging question: What if they had chosen differently? The possibilities of the road not taken are a relentless haunt.In entrancing, lyrical prose, The Mothers asks whether a "what if" can be more powerful than an experience itself. If, as time passes, we must always live in servitude to the decisions of our younger selves, to the communities that have parented us, and to the decisions we make that shape our lives forever.</Cell>
      <Cell>North America</Cell>
      <Cell>United States</Cell>
   </Row>
   <Row>
      <Cell>Bennett, Britt</Cell>
      <Cell>Vanishing Half, The</Cell>
      <Cell>The Vignes twin sisters will always be identical. But after growing up together in a small, southern black community and running away at age sixteen, it’s not just the shape of their daily lives that is different as adults, it’s everything: their families, their communities, their racial identities. Many years later, one sister lives with her black daughter in the same southern town she once tried to escape. The other secretly passes for white, and her white husband knows nothing of her past. Still, even separated by so many miles and just as many lies, the fates of the twins remain intertwined. What will happen to the next generation, when their own daughters’ storylines intersect?</Cell>
      <Cell>North America</Cell>
      <Cell>United States</Cell>
   </Row>
   <Row>
      <Cell>Butler, Octavia</Cell>
      <Cell>Bloodchild and Other Stories</Cell>
      <Cell>Appearing in print for the first time, "Amnesty" is a story of a woman named Noah who works to negotiate the tense and co-dependent relationship between humans and a species of invaders. Also new to this collection is "The Book of Martha" which asks: What would you do if God granted you the ability—and responsibility—to save humanity from itself?Like all of Octavia Butler’s best writing, these works of the imagination are parables of the contemporary world. She proves constant in her vigil, an unblinking pessimist hoping to be proven wrong, and one of contemporary literature’s strongest voices.</Cell>
      <Cell>North America</Cell>
      <Cell>United States</Cell>
   </Row>
   <Row>
      <Cell>Butler, Octavia</Cell>
      <Cell>Kindred </Cell>
      <Cell>Dana, a modern black woman, is celebrating her twenty-sixth birthday with her new husband when she is snatched abruptly from her home in California and transported to the antebellum South. Rufus, the white son of a plantation owner, is drowning, and Dana has been summoned to save him. Dana is drawn back repeatedly through time to the slave quarters, and each time the stay grows longer, more arduous, and more dangerous until it is uncertain whether or not Dana's life will end, long before it has a chance to begin.</Cell>
      <Cell>North America</Cell>
      <Cell>United States</Cell>
   </Row>
   <Row>
      <Cell>Butler, Octavia</Cell>
      <Cell>Seed to Harvest</Cell>
      <Cell>In the late seventeenth century, two immortals meet in an African forest. Anyanwu is a healer, a three-hundred-year-old woman who uses her wisdom to help those around her. The other is Doro, a malevolent despot who has mastered the power of stealing the bodies of others when his wears out. Together they will change the world.

Over the next three centuries, Doro mounts a colossal selective breeding project, attempting to create a master race of telepaths. He succeeds beyond his wildest dreams, splitting the human race down the middle and establishing a new world order dominated by the most manipulative minds on Earth.</Cell>
      <Cell>North America</Cell>
      <Cell>United States</Cell>
   </Row>
   <Row>
      <Cell>Vieux Chauvet, Marie</Cell>
      <Cell>Love, Anger, Madness</Cell>
      <Cell>Presents three novellas that represent a shocking reflection on how families and artists suffer under the harsh government restrictions of Haiti's current oppressive regime.</Cell>
      <Cell>North America</Cell>
      <Cell>Haiti</Cell>
   </Row>
   <Row>
      <Cell>Childress, Alice</Cell>
      <Cell>Short Walk, A</Cell>
      <Cell>Famed dramatist and author Alice Childress portrays her protagonist’s “short walk” through life. During the early half of the twentieth century, Cora James experiences political movements, the easy life of dealing poker in a Harlem card parlor, and the more grueling demands of the vaudeville circuit. She emerges as the woman of stature she always vowed to become.</Cell>
      <Cell>North America</Cell>
      <Cell>United States</Cell>
   </Row>
   <Row>
      <Cell>Cliff, Michelle</Cell>
      <Cell>Abeng</Cell>
      <Cell>Clare is twelve years old, the light-skinned daughter of a middle-class family, growing up among the complex contradictions of class versus color, blood versus history, harsh reality versus delusion, in a colonized country. In language that surrounds us with a richness of meaning and voices, the several strands of young Clare's heritage are explored: the Maroons, who used the conch shell—the abeng—to pass messages as they fought a guerilla struggle against their English enslavers; and the legacy of Clare's white great-great-grandfater, Judge Savage, who burned his hundred slaves on the eve of their emancipation.</Cell>
      <Cell>North America</Cell>
      <Cell>Jamaica</Cell>
   </Row>
   <Row>
      <Cell>Collins, Kathleen</Cell>
      <Cell>What Happened to Interracial Love?</Cell>
      <Cell>Humorous, poignant, perceptive, and full of grace, Kathleen Collins’s stories masterfully blend the quotidian and the profound in a personal, intimate way, exploring deep, far-reaching issues—race, gender, family, and sexuality—that shape the ordinary moments in our lives.In “The Uncle,” a young girl who idolizes her handsome uncle and his beautiful wife makes a haunting discovery about their lives. In “Only Once,” a woman reminisces about her charming daredevil of a lover and his ultimate—and final—act of foolishness.</Cell>
      <Cell>North America</Cell>
      <Cell>United States</Cell>
   </Row>
   <Row>
      <Cell>Danticat, Edwidge</Cell>
      <Cell>Dew Breaker, The</Cell>
      <Cell>We meet him late in life: a quiet man, a good father and husband, a fixture in his Brooklyn neighborhood, a landlord and barber with a terrifying scar across his face. As the book unfolds, moving seamlessly between Haiti in the 1960s and New York City today, we enter the lives of those around him, and learn that he has also kept a vital, dangerous secret. Edwidge Danticat’s brilliant exploration of the “dew breaker”--or torturer--s an unforgettable story of love, remorse, and hope; of personal and political rebellions; and of the compromises we make to move beyond the most intimate brushes with history.</Cell>
      <Cell>North America</Cell>
      <Cell>Haiti/United States</Cell>
   </Row>
   <Row>
      <Cell>Danticat, Edwidge</Cell>
      <Cell>Farming of Bones, The</Cell>
      <Cell>In a 1930s Dominican Republic village, the scream of a woman in labor rings out like the shot heard around Hispaniola. Every detail of the birth scene--the balance of power between the middle-aged Señora and her Haitian maid, the babies' skin color, not to mention which child is to survive--reverberates throughout Edwidge Danticat's "Farming of Bones". In fact, rather than a celebration of fecundity, the unexpected double delivery gels into a metaphor for the military-sponsored mass murder of Haitian emigrants.  An astute observer of human character, Amabelle Désir is also a conduit for the author's tart, poetic prose. Her lover, Sebastian, has "arms as wide as one of my bare thighs," while the Señora's complicit officer husband is "still shorter than the average man, even in his military boots."The orphaned Amabelle comes to assume almost messianic proportions, but she is entirely fictional, as is the town of Alegría where the tale begins. The genocide and exodus, however, are factual. Indeed, the atrocities committed by Dominican president Rafael Trujillo's army back in 1937 rival those of Duvalier's Touton Macoutes. History has rendered Trujillo's carnage much less visible than Duvalier's, but no less painful. As Amabelle's father once told her, "Misery won't touch you gentle. It always leaves its thumbprints on you; sometimes it leaves them for others to see, sometimes for nobody but you to know of." </Cell>
      <Cell>North America</Cell>
      <Cell>Haiti/United States</Cell>
   </Row>
   <Row>
      <Cell>Diaz, Junot</Cell>
      <Cell>Brief Wondrous Life of Oscar Wao, The</Cell>
      <Cell>Oscar is a sweet but disastrously overweight ghetto nerd who—from the New Jersey home he shares with his old world mother and rebellious sister—dreams of becoming the Dominican J.R.R. Tolkien and, most of all, finding love. But Oscar may never get what he wants. Blame the fukú—a curse that has haunted Oscar’s family for generations, following them on their epic journey from Santo Domingo to the USA.</Cell>
      <Cell>North America</Cell>
      <Cell>Dominican Republic/United States</Cell>
   </Row>
   <Row>
      <Cell>Diaz, Junot</Cell>
      <Cell>This is How You Lose Her</Cell>
      <Cell>On a beach in the Dominican Republic, a doomed relationship flounders. In a New Jersey laundry room, a woman does her lover’s washing and thinks about his wife. In Boston, a man buys his love child, his only son, a first baseball bat and glove. At the heart of these stories is the irrepressible, irresistible Yunior, a young hardhead whose longing for love is equaled only by his recklessness--and by the extraordinary women he loves and loses.</Cell>
      <Cell>North America</Cell>
      <Cell>Dominican Republic/United States</Cell>
   </Row>
   <Row>
      <Cell>Fagunwa, D.O.</Cell>
      <Cell>Forest of a Thousand Daemons</Cell>
      <Cell>A triumph of the mythic imagination, the narrative unfolds in a landscape where, true to Yoruba cosmology, human, natural, and supernatural beings are compellingly and wonderfully alive at once: a world of warriors, sages and kings; magical trees and snake people; spirits, Ghommids, and bog-trolls. Here are the adventures of Akara-ogunson of a brave warrior and wicked witchas he journeys into the forest, encountering and dealing with all-too-real unforeseen forces, engaging in dynamic spiritual and moral relationships with personifications of his fate, projections of the terrors that haunt man.</Cell>
      <Cell>Africa</Cell>
      <Cell>Nigeria</Cell>
   </Row>
   <Row>
      <Cell>Fauset, Jessie Redmon</Cell>
      <Cell>Plum Bun: A Novel Without a Moral</Cell>
      <Cell>Plum Bun is the story of Angela Murray, a young Black girl who discovers she can pass for white. After the death of her parents, Angela moves to New York to escape the racism she believes is her only obstacle to opportunity. What she soon discovers is that being a woman has its own burdens that don't fade with the color of one's skin, and that love and marriage might not offer her salvation.</Cell>
      <Cell>North America</Cell>
      <Cell>United States</Cell>
   </Row>
   <Row>
      <Cell>Fauset, Jessie Redmon</Cell>
      <Cell>There is Confusion</Cell>
      <Cell>Set in early twentieth-century New York City, "There Is Confusion" tells the story of Joanna Marshall, a talented dancer willing to sacrifice everything for success; Maggie Ellersley, an extraordinarily beautiful girl determined to leave her working-class background behind; and Peter Bye, a clever would-be surgeon who is driven by his love for Joanna.  As children, Maggie, Joanna, and Peter support each other's dreams. But when romance threatens to change the balance of their friendship, Joanna makes two irrevocable decisions--and sets off a chain of events that wreaks havoc with all of their lives.</Cell>
      <Cell>North America</Cell>
      <Cell>United States</Cell>
   </Row>
   <Row>
      <Cell>Forrest, Leon</Cell>
      <Cell>Divine Days</Cell>
      <Cell>A unanimous chorus of critical acclaim greeted this powerful novel last year—one of the most significant works of African-American fiction since Ralph Ellison's Invisible Man. This huge oratorio of a novel unfolds over seven days in the life of Joubert Jones, an aspiring playwright making ends meet tending bar at his Aunt Eloise's Night Lounge. A Rabelaisian cast of characters and a Shakespearean range of voices crowd the pages of this book, an infinitely rich and suggestive tapestry of Black American life and identity.</Cell>
      <Cell>North America</Cell>
      <Cell>United States</Cell>
   </Row>
   <Row>
      <Cell>Forrest, Leon</Cell>
      <Cell>There is a Tree More Ancient Than Eden</Cell>
      <Cell>Leon Forrest, acclaimed author of "Divine Days", uses a remarkable verbal intensity to evoke human tragedy, injustice, and spirituality in his writing. As Toni Morrison has said, “All of Forrest’s novels explore the complex legacy of Afro-Americans. Like an insistent tide this history . . . swells and recalls America’s past. . . . Brooding, hilarious, acerbic and profoundly valued life has no more astute observer than Leon Forrest.” All of that is on display here in two novels that give readers a breathtaking view of the human experience, filled with humor and pathos.</Cell>
      <Cell>North America</Cell>
      <Cell>United States</Cell>
   </Row>
   <Row>
      <Cell>Greenidge, Kaitlyn</Cell>
      <Cell>Libertie</Cell>
      <Cell>Coming of age in a free Black community in Reconstruction-era Brooklyn, Libertie Sampson is all too aware that her purposeful mother, a practicing physician, has a vision for their future together: Libertie is to go to medical school and practice alongside her. But Libertie, drawn more to music than science, feels stifled by her mother’s choices and is hungry for something else—is there really only one way to have an autonomous life? And she is constantly reminded that, unlike her light-skinned mother, Libertie will not be able to pass for white. When a young man from Haiti proposes to Libertie and promises she will be his equal on the island, she accepts, only to discover that she is still subordinate to him and all men. As she tries to parse what freedom actually means for a Black woman, Libertie struggles with where she might find it—for herself and for generations to come.</Cell>
      <Cell>North America</Cell>
      <Cell>United States</Cell>
   </Row>
   <Row>
      <Cell>Gyasi, Yaa</Cell>
      <Cell>Homegoing</Cell>
      <Cell>Two half-sisters, Effia and Esi, are born into different villages in eighteenth-century Ghana. Effia is married off to an Englishman and lives in comfort in the palatial rooms of Cape Coast Castle. Unbeknownst to Effia, her sister, Esi, is imprisoned beneath her in the castle’s dungeons, sold with thousands of others into the Gold Coast’s booming slave trade, and shipped off to America, where her children and grandchildren will be raised in slavery. One thread of Homegoing follows Effia’s descendants through centuries of warfare in Ghana, as the Fante and Asante nations wrestle with the slave trade and British colonization. The other thread follows Esi and her children into America. From the plantations of the South to the Civil War and the Great Migration, from the coal mines of Pratt City, Alabama, to the jazz clubs and dope houses of twentieth-century Harlem, right up through the present day, Homegoing makes history visceral, and captures, with singular and stunning immediacy, how the memory of captivity came to be inscribed in the soul of a nation.</Cell>
      <Cell>North America</Cell>
      <Cell>United States</Cell>
   </Row>
   <Row>
      <Cell>Hughes, Langston</Cell>
      <Cell>Ways of White Folks, The</Cell>
      <Cell>In these acrid and poignant stories, Hughes depicted black people colliding--sometimes humorously, more often tragically--with whites in the 1920s and '30s.</Cell>
      <Cell>North America</Cell>
      <Cell>United States</Cell>
   </Row>
   <Row>
      <Cell>Hurston, Zora Neale</Cell>
      <Cell>Their Eyes Were Watching God</Cell>
      <Cell>One of the most important works of twentieth-century American literature, Zora Neale Hurston's beloved 1937 classic, Their Eyes Were Watching God, is an enduring Southern love story sparkling with wit, beauty, and heartfelt wisdom. Told in the captivating voice of a woman who refuses to live in sorrow, bitterness, fear, or foolish romantic dreams, it is the story of fair-skinned, fiercely independent Janie Crawford, and her evolving selfhood through three marriages and a life marked by poverty, trials, and purpose.</Cell>
      <Cell>North America</Cell>
      <Cell>United States</Cell>
   </Row>
   <Row>
      <Cell>James, Marlon</Cell>
      <Cell>Black Leopard, Red Wolf</Cell>
      <Cell>In the stunning first novel in Marlon James's Dark Star trilogy, myth, fantasy, and history come together to explore what happens when a mercenary is hired to find a missing child. Tracker is known far and wide for his skills as a hunter: "He has a nose," people say. Engaged to track down a mysterious boy who disappeared three years earlier, Tracker breaks his own rule of always working alone when he finds himself part of a group that comes together to search for the boy. The band is a hodgepodge, full of unusual characters with secrets of their own, including a shape-shifting man-animal known as Leopard.As Tracker follows the boy's scent--from one ancient city to another; into dense forests and across deep rivers--he and the band are set upon by creatures intent on destroying them. As he struggles to survive, Tracker starts to wonder: Who, really, is this boy? Why has he been missing for so long? Why do so many people want to keep Tracker from finding him? And perhaps the most important questions of all: Who is telling the truth, and who is lying?</Cell>
      <Cell>North America</Cell>
      <Cell>Jamaica/United States</Cell>
   </Row>
   <Row>
      <Cell>James, Marlon</Cell>
      <Cell>Book of Night Women, The</Cell>
      <Cell>"The Book of Night Women" is a sweeping, startling novel, a true tour de force of both voice and storytelling. It is the story of Lilith, born into slavery on a Jamaican sugar plantation at the end of the eighteenth century. Even at her birth, the slave women around her recognize a dark power that they—and she—will come to both revere and fear. The Night Women, as they call themselves, have long been plotting a slave revolt, and as Lilith comes of age and reveals the extent of her power, they see her as the key to their plans. But when she begins to understand her own feelings and desires and identity, Lilith starts to push at the edges of what is imaginable for the life of a slave woman in Jamaica, and risks becoming the conspiracy’s weak link. Lilith’s story overflows with high drama and heartbreak, and life on the plantation is rife with dangerous secrets, unspoken jealousies, inhuman violence, and very human emotion—between slave and master, between slave and overseer, and among the slaves themselves. Lilith finds herself at the heart of it all.</Cell>
      <Cell>North America</Cell>
      <Cell>Jamaica/United States</Cell>
   </Row>
   <Row>
      <Cell>James, Marlon</Cell>
      <Cell>Brief History of Seven Killings, A</Cell>
      <Cell>On December 3, 1976, just before the Jamaican general election and two days before Bob Marley was to play the Smile Jamaica Concert, gunmen stormed his house, machine guns blazing. The attack nearly killed the Reggae superstar, his wife, and his manager, and injured several others. Marley would go on to perform at the free concert on December 5, but he left the country the next day, not to return for two years. Deftly spanning decades and continents and peopled with a wide range of charactera, assassins, journalists, drug dealers, and even ghosts. "A Brief History of Seven Killings" is the fictional exploration of that dangerous and unstable time and its bloody aftermath, from the streets and slums of Kingston in the '70s, to the crack wars in '80s New York, to a radically altered Jamaica in the '90s. Brilliantly inventive and stunningly ambitious, this novel is a revealing modern epic that will secure Marlon James’ place among the great literary talents of his generation.</Cell>
      <Cell>North America</Cell>
      <Cell>Jamaica/United States</Cell>
   </Row>
   <Row>
      <Cell>Jones, Edward P.</Cell>
      <Cell>Known World, The</Cell>
      <Cell>"The Known World" tells the story of Henry Townsend, a black farmer and former slave who falls under the tutelage of William Robbins, the most powerful man in Manchester County, Virginia. Making certain he never circumvents the law, Townsend runs his affairs with unusual discipline. But when death takes him unexpectedly, his widow, Caldonia, can't uphold the estate's order, and chaos ensues. Jones has woven a footnote of history into an epic that takes an unflinching look at slavery in all its moral complexities.</Cell>
      <Cell>North America</Cell>
      <Cell>United States</Cell>
   </Row>
   <Row>
      <Cell>Jones, Gayl</Cell>
      <Cell>Corregidora</Cell>
      <Cell>Here is Gayl Jones's classic novel, the tale of blues singer Ursa, consumed by her hatred of the nineteenth-century slave master who fathered both her grandmother and mother.</Cell>
      <Cell>North America</Cell>
      <Cell>United States</Cell>
   </Row>
   <Row>
      <Cell>Keene, John</Cell>
      <Cell>Counternarratives</Cell>
      <Cell>Conjuring slavery and witchcraft, and with bewitching powers all its own, Counternarratives continually spins history―and storytelling―on its headRanging from the 17th century to our current moment, and crossing multiple continents, Counternarratives' stories and novellas draw upon memoirs, newspaper accounts, detective stories, interrogation transcripts, and speculative fiction to create new and strange perspectives on our past and present. “An Outtake” chronicles an escaped slave’s take on liberty and the American Revolution;"The Strange History of Our Lady of the Sorrows" presents a bizarre series of events that unfold in a nineteenth-century Kentucky convent; "The Aeronauts" soars between bustling Philadelphia, still-rustic Washington, and the theater of the U.S. Civil War; “Rivers,” presents a free Jim meeting up decades later with his former raftmate Huckleberry Finn; and in "Acrobatique," the subject of a famous Edgar Degas painting talks back.</Cell>
      <Cell>North America</Cell>
      <Cell>United States</Cell>
   </Row>
   <Row>
      <Cell>Kincaid, Jamaica</Cell>
      <Cell>Annie John</Cell>
      <Cell>"Annie John" is a haunting and provocative story of a young girl growing up on the island of Antigua. A classic coming-of-age story in the tradition of The Catcher in the Rye and A Portrait of the Artist as a Young Man, Kincaid’s novel focuses on a universal, tragic, and often comic theme: the loss of childhood. Annie’s voice—urgent, demanding to be heard—is one that will not soon be forgotten by readers.An adored only child, Annie has until recently lived an idyllic life. She is inseparable from her beautiful mother, a powerful presence, who is the very center of the little girl’s existence. Loved and cherished, Annie grows and thrives within her mother’s benign shadow. Looking back on her childhood, she reflects, “It was in such a paradise that I lived.” When she turns twelve, however, Annie’s life changes, in ways that are often mysterious to her. She begins to question the cultural assumptions of her island world; at school she instinctively rebels against authority; and most frighteningly, her mother, seeing Annie as a “young lady,” ceases to be the source of unconditional adoration and takes on the new and unfamiliar guise of adversary. At the end of her school years, Annie decides to leave Antigua and her family, but not without a measure of sorrow, especially for the mother she once knew and never ceases to mourn. “For I could not be sure,” she reflects, “whether for the rest of my life I would be able to tell when it was really my mother and when it was really her shadow standing between me and the rest of the world."</Cell>
      <Cell>North America</Cell>
      <Cell>Antigua/United States</Cell>
   </Row>
   <Row>
      <Cell>McKay, Claude</Cell>
      <Cell>Amiable With Big Teeth</Cell>
      <Cell>At once a penetrating satire of political machinations in Depression-era Harlem and a far-reaching story of global intrigue and romance, Amiable with Big Teeth plunges into the concerns, anxieties, hopes, and dreams of African-Americans at a moment of crisis for the soul of Harlem—and America. </Cell>
      <Cell>North America</Cell>
      <Cell>United States</Cell>
   </Row>
   <Row>
      <Cell>McKay, Claude</Cell>
      <Cell>Romance in Marseilles</Cell>
      <Cell>Claude McKay's "Romance in Marseille" traces the adventures of a rowdy troupe of dockworkers, prostitutes, and political organizers--collectively straight and queer, disabled and able-bodied, African, European, Caribbean, and American. Set largely in the culture-blending Vieux Port of Marseille at the height of the Jazz Age, the novel takes flight along with Lafala, an acutely disabled but abruptly wealthy West African sailor. While stowing away on a transatlantic freighter, Lafala is discovered and locked in a frigid closet. Badly frostbitten by the time the boat docks, the once-nimble dancer loses both of his lower legs, emerging from life-saving surgery as what he terms "an amputated man." Thanks to an improbably successful lawsuit against the shipping line, however, Lafala scores big in the litigious United States. Feeling flush after his legal payout, Lafala doubles back to Marseille and resumes his trans-African affair with Aslima, a Moroccan courtesan. With its scenes of Black bodies fighting for pleasure and liberty even when stolen, shipped, and sold for parts, McKay's novel explores the heritage of slavery amid an unforgiving modern economy.</Cell>
      <Cell>North America</Cell>
      <Cell>United States</Cell>
   </Row>
   <Row>
      <Cell>Morrison, Toni</Cell>
      <Cell>Beloved</Cell>
      <Cell>Set in post-Civil War Ohio, it is the story of Sethe, an escaped slave who has lost a husband and buried a child; who has withstood savagery and not gone mad. Sethe, who now lives in a small house on the edge of town with her daughter, Denver, her mother-in-law, Baby Suggs, and a disturbing, mesmerizing apparition who calls herself Beloved. Sethe works at "beating back the past," but it makes itself heard and felt incessantly: in her memory; in Denver's fear of the world outside the house; in the sadness that consumes Baby Suggs; in the arrival of Paul D, a fellow former slave; and, most powerfully, in Beloved, whose childhood belongs to the hideous logic of slavery and who has now come from the "place over there" to claim retribution for what she lost and for what was taken from her. Sethe's struggle to keep Beloved from gaining possession of the present--and to throw off the long-dark legacy of the past--is at the center of this spellbinding novel.</Cell>
      <Cell>North America</Cell>
      <Cell>United States</Cell>
   </Row>
   <Row>
      <Cell>Morrison, Toni</Cell>
      <Cell>Jazz</Cell>
      <Cell>It is winter, barely three days into 1926, seven years after Armistice; we are in the scintillating City, around Lenox Avenue, "when all the wars are over and there will never be another one...At last, at last, everything's ahead...Here comes the new. Look out. There goes the sad stuff. The bad stuff. The things-nobody-could-help stuff." But amid the euphoric decisiveness, a tragedy ensues among people who had train-danced into the City, from points south and west, in search of promise.Joe Trace--in his fifties, door-to-door salesman of Cleopatra beauty products, erstwhile devoted husband--shoots to death his lover of three months, impetuous, eighteen-year-old Dorcas ("Everything was like a picture show to her"). At the funeral, his determined, hard-working wife, Violet, herself a hairdresser--who is given to stumbling into dark mental cracks, and who talks mostly to birds--tries with a knife to disfigure the corpse. In a dazzling act of jazz-like improvisation, moving seamlessly in and out of past, present, and future, a mysterious voice--whose identity is a matter of each reader's imagination--weaves this brilliant fiction, at the same time showing how its blues are informed by the brutal exigencies of slavery.</Cell>
      <Cell>North America</Cell>
      <Cell>United States</Cell>
   </Row>
   <Row>
      <Cell>Morrison, Toni</Cell>
      <Cell>Paradise</Cell>
      <Cell>"Paradise" begins deep in Oklahoma early one morning in 1976, when nine men from Ruby (pop. 360), in defense of "the one all-black town worth the pain," assault the nearby Convent and the women in it. From the town's ancestral origins in 1890 to the fateful day of the assault, Paradise tells the story of a people ever mindful of the relationship between their spectacular history and a void "Out There . . . where random and organized evil erupted when and where it chose." Richly imagined and elegantly composed, Paradise weaves a powerful mystery.</Cell>
      <Cell>North America</Cell>
      <Cell>United States</Cell>
   </Row>
   <Row>
      <Cell>Morrison, Toni</Cell>
      <Cell>Song of Solomon</Cell>
      <Cell>Toni Morrison's "Song of Solomon", a novel of large beauty and power, creates a magical world out of four generations of black life in America, a world we enter on the day of the birth of Macon Dead, Jr. (known as Milkman), son of the richest black family in a mid-western town; the day on which the lonely insurance man, Robert Smith, poised in blue silk wings, attempts to fly from a steeple of the hospital, a Black Icarus looking homeward...We see Milkman growing up in his father's money-haunted, death-haunted house with his silent sisters and strangely passive mother, beginning to move outward--through his profound love and combat with his friend Guitar...through Guitar's mad and loving commitment to the secret avengers called the Seven Days...through Milkman's exotic, imprisoning affair with his love-blind cousin, Hagar...and through his unconscious apprenticeship to his mystical Aunt Pilate, who saved his life before he was born.And we follow him as he strikes out alone; moving first toward adventure and then--as the unspoken truth about his family and his own buried heritage announces itself--toward an adventurous and crucial embrace of life.</Cell>
      <Cell>North America</Cell>
      <Cell>United States</Cell>
   </Row>
   <Row>
      <Cell>Morrison, Toni</Cell>
      <Cell>Tar Baby</Cell>
      <Cell>Jadine Childs is a Black fashion model with a white patron, a white boyfriend, and a coat made out of ninety perfect sealskins. Son is a Black fugitive who embodies everything she loathes and desires. As Morrison follows their affair, which plays out from the Caribbean to Manhattan and the deep South, she charts all the nuances of obligation and betrayal between Blacks and whites, masters and servants, and men and women.</Cell>
      <Cell>North America</Cell>
      <Cell>United States</Cell>
   </Row>
   <Row>
      <Cell>Petry, Ann</Cell>
      <Cell>Street, The</Cell>
      <Cell>"The Street" tells the poignant, often heartbreaking story of Lutie Johnson, a young black woman, and her spirited struggle to raise her son amid the violence, poverty, and racial dissonance of Harlem in the late 1940s.</Cell>
      <Cell>North America</Cell>
      <Cell>United States</Cell>
   </Row>
   <Row>
      <Cell>Polite, Carlene Hatcher</Cell>
      <Cell>The Flagellants</Cell>
      <Cell>Ideal and Jimson are a young black couple living in New York City, whose escalating verbal and physical clashes reflect the casual brutality inflicted on African Americans.</Cell>
      <Cell>North America</Cell>
      <Cell>United States</Cell>
   </Row>
   <Row>
      <Cell>Pushkin, Alexander</Cell>
      <Cell>Novels, Tales, and Journeys</Cell>
      <Cell>The father of Russian literature, Pushkin is beloved not only for his poetry but also for his brilliant stories, which range from dramatic tales of love, obsession, and betrayal to dark fables and sparkling comic masterpieces, from satirical epistolary tales and romantic adventures in the manner of Sir Walter Scott to imaginative historical fiction and the haunting dreamworld of "The Queen of Spades." The five short stories of The Late Tales of Ivan Petrovich Belkin are lightly humorous and yet reveal astonishing human depths, and his short novel, The Captain's Daughter, has been called the most perfect book in Russian literature.</Cell>
      <Cell>Europe</Cell>
      <Cell>Russia</Cell>
   </Row>
   <Row>
      <Cell>Schuyler, George S.</Cell>
      <Cell>Black No More</Cell>
      <Cell>The landmark comic satire that asks, “What would happen if all Black people in America turned white?” It’s New Year’s Day 1933 in New York City, and Max Disher, a young Black man, has just found out that a certain Dr. Junius Crookman has discovered a mysterious process that allows people to bleach their skin white—a new way to “solve the American race problem.” Max leaps at the opportunity, and after a brief stay at the Crookman Sanitarium, he becomes Matthew Fisher, a white man who is able to attain everything he has ever wanted: money, power, good liquor, and the white woman who rejected him when he was black. Lampooning myths of white supremacy and racial purity and caricaturing prominent African American leaders like W. E. B. Du Bois, Madam C. J. Walker, and Marcus Garvey, Black No More is a masterwork of speculative fiction and a hilarious satire of America’s obsession with race.</Cell>
      <Cell>North America</Cell>
      <Cell>United States</Cell>
   </Row>
   <Row>
      <Cell>Smith, Zadie</Cell>
      <Cell>White Teeth</Cell>
      <Cell>At the center of this invigorating novel are two unlikely friends, Archie Jones and Samad Iqbal. Hapless veterans of World War II, Archie and Samad and their families become agents of England’s irrevocable transformation. A second marriage to Clara Bowden, a beautiful, albeit tooth-challenged, Jamaican half his age, quite literally gives Archie a second lease on life, and produces Irie, a knowing child whose personality doesn’t quite match her name (Jamaican for “no problem”). Samad’s late-in-life arranged marriage (he had to wait for his bride to be born), produces twin sons whose separate paths confound Iqbal’s every effort to direct them, and a renewed, if selective, submission to his Islamic faith. Set against London’s racial and cultural tapestry, venturing across the former empire and into the past as it barrels toward the future, White Teeth revels in the ecstatic hodgepodge of modern life, flirting with disaster, confounding expectations, and embracing the comedy of daily existence.</Cell>
      <Cell>Europe</Cell>
      <Cell>England</Cell>
   </Row>
   <Row>
      <Cell>Thiong'o, Ngugi Wa</Cell>
      <Cell>Devil on the Cross</Cell>
      <Cell>"Devil on the Cross" tells the tragic story of Wariinga, a young woman who moves from a rural Kenyan town to the capital, Nairobi, only to be exploited by her boss and later by a corrupt businessman. As she struggles to survive, Wariinga begins to realize that her problems are only symptoms of a larger societal malaise and that much of the misfortune stems from the Western, capitalist influences on her country. An impassioned cry for a Kenya free of dictatorship and for African writers to work in their own local dialects, "Devil on the Cross "has had a profound influence on Africa and on post-colonial African literature.</Cell>
      <Cell>Africa</Cell>
      <Cell>Kenya</Cell>
   </Row>
   <Row>
      <Cell>Thiong'o, Ngugi Wa</Cell>
      <Cell>Petals of Blood</Cell>
      <Cell>The puzzling murder of three African directors of a foreign-owned brewery sets the scene for this fervent, hard-hitting novel about disillusionment in independent Kenya. A deceptively simple tale, Petals of Blood is on the surface a suspenseful investigation of a spectacular triple murder in upcountry Kenya. Yet as the intertwined stories of the four suspects unfold, a devastating picture emerges of a modern third-world nation whose frustrated people feel their leaders have failed them time after time. First published in 1977, this novel was so explosive that its author was imprisoned without charges by the Kenyan government. His incarceration was so shocking that newspapers around the world called attention to the case, and protests were raised by human-rights groups, scholars, and writers, including James Baldwin, Toni Morrison, Donald Barthelme, Harold Pinter, and Margaret Drabble.</Cell>
      <Cell>Africa</Cell>
      <Cell>Kenya</Cell>
   </Row>
   <Row>
      <Cell>West, Dorothy</Cell>
      <Cell>The Wedding</Cell>
      <Cell>Set on bucolic Martha's Vineyard in the 1950s, The Wedding tells the story of life in the Oval, a proud, insular community made up of the best and brightest of the East Coast's black bourgeoisie.  Within this inner circle of "blue-vein society," we witness the prominent Coles family gather for the wedding of the loveliest daughter, Shelby, who could have chosen from "a whole area of eligible men of the right colors and the right professions." Instead, she has fallen in love with and is about to be married to Meade Wyler, a white jazz musician from New York. A shock wave breaks over the Oval as its longtime members grapple with the changing face of its community.   With elegant, luminous prose, Dorothy West crowns her literary career by illustrating one family's struggle to break the shackles of race and class.</Cell>
      <Cell>North America</Cell>
      <Cell>United States</Cell>
   </Row>
</Table>
